Finding Aid for Stuart Hoffman Perry papers, 1874-1966
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Stuart Hoffman Perry papers 1874-1966
Perry, Stuart Hoffman, 1874-1957.
53 oversize volumes
2 linear feet
852156 Aa 2; AC
Publisher of the Adrian Telegram at Adrian, Michigan. Scrapbooks containing newspaper editorials primarily on political subjects; and miscellaneous correspondence and articles concerning his newspaper work; notes, 1899-1950, relating to his foreign travels, papers, 1935-1955, concerning his interest in meteorites; and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Part of the collection came from Donald Bates, president of the Adrian State Bank (donor no. 5175 ) in 1971. These materials had been stored at the bank buildings. The remainder came from C. Kenneth Wesley (donor no. 3543 ) in 1972.
The collection is open to research.
Stuart Hoffman Perry was born October 13, 1874 in Pontiac, Michigan, the son of Aaron and Sally Hoffman Perry. He received his B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1894. He received his law degree in 1896, then began the practice of law in Pontiac with his father. In 1901, he decided to enter newspaper work in association with Harry Coleman who was then publisher of the Pontiac Daily Press. Stuart Perry became managing editor of the recently established newspaper. In 1902, he purchased the St. Johns News which he published until 1906. In 1907, he purchased the Adrian Telegram and becoming editor and publisher, positions he would hold until his death in 1957. In 1927, in partnership with others, Perry purchased The Evening News of Monroe, Michigan. He would serve as vice president of this organization until 1957.
Though Perry never practice law after 1901, he continued to be active in legal organizations, serving on various committees of the Michigan State Bar, and a member of the Michigan Judicial Council. He also was a member of governmental agencies, notably the Michigan Advisory Council on State Finance (1931-1932) and the Michigan Civil Service Commission (1937-1938).
Always interested in science, Perry took up the study of meteorites and engaged in research on the composition and structure of meteoric irons. At one time, he had one of the largest private collections of meteorites which he later donated to public and university museums.
Stuart Hoffman Perry died February 14, 1957.
The collection has been arranged into the following series: Adrian Telegram, Correspondence, Speeches and Articles, Other activities and interests, Programs of meetings and annual dinners, Newspaper clippings, and Photographs.
Subjects:
Adrian (Mich.); Adrian telegram.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Ann Arbor news.; Astronomy--Michigan--Adrian.; Journalism--Michigan--Adrian.; Journalists--Michigan--Adrian.; Meteorites.; Michigan--Politics and government--1899-1916.; Michigan--Politics and government--1917-1921.; Michigan--Politics and government--1922-1928.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Michigan--Politics and government--1939-1945.; Michigan--Politics and government--1946-1960.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Newspaper publishing--Michigan--Adrian.; Voyages and travels.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Buildings--Michigan--Stanton.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Stanton.; Camping--1881-1890.; Caseville (Mich.); Delta Chi Fraternity. University of Michigan Chapter.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Michigan--Stanton.; France--1923.; Great Britain--1923.; Huron River (Oakland County-Monroe County, Mich.); Journalists--Michigan--Adrian.; Military art and science.; Military camps.; Panama.; Panama Canal (Panama); Photographers.; Québec (Québec); Railroad stations--Michigan--Stanton.; Stanton (Mich.)--Buildings.; Stanton (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Stanton (Mich.)--Railroad stations.; United States. Navy.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; University of Michigan--Student housing--1891-1900.; University of Michigan--Students--1891-1900.; War damage.; West Indies.; World War, 1914-1918.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Adrian Telegram
  - Scrapbooks containing editorials written for the newspaper, 1911-1954, 51 volumes (Volume 1)
  - Scrapbooks containing editorials written by others, 1961, 1965-1966, 2 volumes (Volume 2)
  - Advertising revenues of the Adrian Telegram, 1907-1916
    - 1907-1911 (Box 1)
    - 1914-1916 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous 1907-1942 (Box 1)
  - Student paper by Herbert G. Wilson, "The Adrian Telegram" 1918 (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1892-1896 (Box 1)
    (include letter from James B. Angell, July 15, 1896)
  - 1897 (Box 1)
  - 1899 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1904 (Box 1)
  - July-August 1904 (Box 1)
  - September-December 1904 (Box 1)
  - 1906-1907 (Box 1)
  - 1908 (Box 1)
  - 1909-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1914-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917 (Box 1)
  - January-June 1918 (Box 1)
  - July-December 1918 (Box 1)
  - 1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924-1955 (Box 1)
- Speeches and Articles
  - Undated 1885-1899 (Box 1)
  - 1900-1909 (Box 1)
  - 1910-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917-1919 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1923 (Box 1)
  - 1924-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - 1935-1944 (Box 1)
- Other activities and interests
  - University of Michigan student and alumni
    - Scrapbook containing programs of concerts and other event attended, 1892-1899 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook concerning student activities and alumni meetings, 1892-1898 (Box 1)
  - Biographical and genealogical information 1913-1946, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Travel notes 1899-1950, photocopies (Box 2)
  - Diary, trip to Europe 1950 (Box 2)
  - Meteorite collection 1935-1955, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Diaries (brief entries), account books, cash books 1891-1908, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Adrian, Michigan printed material 1894-1927 (Box 2)
  - Aaron Perry (father) papers 1874-1926 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous and memorabilia 1892-1945, 4 folders (Box 2)
- Programs of meetings and annual dinners
  - 1924 (Box 2)
  - 1925-1929 (Box 2)
  - 1930-1939 (Box 2)
  - 1940-1944 (Box 2)
- Newspaper clippings
  - Undated 1904-1905 (Box 2)
  - 1907 (Box 2)
  - 1911-1916 (Box 2)
  - 1920-1952 (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Portraits (also group portraits, and portraits of others) (Box 2)
  - Caseville camping trip circa 1888 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan student photos 1890s (Box 2)
    (also include Ann Arbor views)
  - World War I service (Box 2)
  - Travels
    - Panama Canal (during construction) 1913, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - England and France 1923 (Box 2)
    - Naval Cruise (West Indies and Panama) 1923, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (include Stanton, Michigan) (Box 2)